# Emily **Groenendal**

Freelance Web Design And Social Media Management

Address Grand Rapids, MI, 49503

**LinkedIn** linkedin.com/in/emilykayg

**Phone** 720-323-8220

**E-mail** Emily.kaygr@gmail.com

Experienced Web Design and Tech Support Specialist with over 3 years of experience in Web and Social Media Design. Excellent reputation for resolving problems, improving customer satisfaction, and driving overall operational improvements. Motivated to learn, grow and excel in Web Development and Marketing.

#### Skills

Adobe Photoshop   Illustrator	
Copywriting and Editing	
Wordpress, Divi, Squarespace, Wix	
Organizational Skills	
Communication Skills	
Spanish Language proficient	
Technical Support and Customer Service	
Web Design	
HTML/CSS	

## **Work History**

#### 2019-01 - Current

# Web Design and Tech Support (Contract)

Outreach, Inc., Colorado Springs, CO

- Worked with Outreach Digital customers to understand needs and provide Web Design, Tech Support (ongoing website support) and Social Media assistance.
- Offered Tech Support via email, chat and telephone.
- Manage onboarding process for new customers, including gathering website
  information and requirements, managing job assignments with vendors (e.g.
  Upwork) when necessary, and successful website delivery to customer through
  training and acceptance.
- Migrate websites over to Outreach's website platform using WordPress visual builder.
- Build new templates for church's using latest design trends.
- Proactively develop training videos and how to's for Outreach Digital

knowledge base.

- Social Media Posts design.
- Facebook Ad Creation.
- Email Marketing copy writing.

#### 2018-11 - Current Soc

## Social Media (Contract)

Freelance, Grand Rapids, MI

- Used Facebook Publishing tools and Buffer/Hootsuite/Loomly to analyze conversion rates across multiple digital channels.
- Increased customer engagement through social media.
- Identified target market and key segments through in-depth analysis of markets and related trends.
- Devised strategies and roadmaps to support product vision and value to business.
- Analyzed and reported social media and online marketing campaign results.
- Used Loomly and HeyOrca for post scheduling and planning.
- Designed content using Canva, Photoshop, and Illustrator.
- Helped clients develop website portals and social media pages to promote businesses.
- Integrated social media pages with Websites (Squarepace, Wordpress and Wix).
- Created catalogs for Shopify business. Including integration with Facebook Business Manager and Instagram.

#### 2017-09 - 2019-02 **S**

# Social Media Manager

Awaken Church And 5twelve City Church, Austin, TX

- Created, scheduled and repurposed curated content for Social Media channels using their unique brand voice.
- Implemented strategies to reach specific social media goals.
- Designed flyers, Facebook ads, and logos for print and online platforms using Photoshop and Illustrator.
- Developed entire marketing strategy, brand and design.
- Increased page following by 270%.
- Planned and organized social events: scheduling, marketing, design and decor.
- Redesigned and built their church website on Wordpress using Divi Builder.
- App creation and management.
- Analyzed and reported social media and online marketing campaign results.

#### 2018-11 - 2018-12

# Social Media Manager

EpicPay, Frisco, TX

- Identified target market and key segments through in-depth analysis of markets and related trends.
- Monitored online presence of company's brand to engage with users and strengthen customer relationships.
- Devised strategies and road maps to support product vision and value to business.

- Analyzed and reported social media and online marketing campaign results.
- Used HeyOrca social media platform to plan social media post content.
- Designed social media posts while keeping with company's unique brand voice and marketing strategy.

### **Education**

#### 2020-05 - 2021-03

## Full-Stack Web Development: Full-Stack Web Development

Michigan State University - East Lansing, MI

Along with self study, I am working on the boot camp pre-work and will begin classes Sept. 2020.

## No Degree: Elementary Education

Colorado Christian University - Denver, CO

## No Degree: Spanish Teacher Education

Rock Valley College - Rockford, IL

### Software

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe Photoshop

Social Media Planning Apps | Hootsuite, Loomly, Later,
Buffer, HeyOrca

Wordpress

# Languages

Spanish

# **Interests**

Web Development (HTML,CSS, Javascript)